<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Jovi K</title><link>https://example.com/project/</link><atom:link href="https://example.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu2110016f7bd3295c7cefa875f5c42664_171153_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://example.com/project/</link></image><item><title>II. Plasma Instability in Hall Thrusters - A Numerical Study</title><link>https://example.com/project/plasma_ii/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/plasma_ii/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hall effect thrusters (HETs) are widely used in space propulsion systems due to their high thrust-to-power ratio, high specific impulse, high efficiency, and simple structure. However, partial plasma confinement is fundamental to Hall Thrusters Physics and leads to a variety of instabilities such as Modified Two Stream Instability and Electron Cyclotron Drift Instability that negatively impact the efficiency and overall performance of the thrusters. In this study, we numerically solve the general dispersion relation for Hall thrusters to better understand these instabilities and improve the design process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Designing Twisted Bilayer Graphene Based Devices</title><link>https://example.com/project/thesis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>The investigation of the characteristics of van der Waals heterostructures is a rapidly growing area of research in condensed matter physics, with significant potential but still in its infancy. Graphene, known as a &amp;ldquo;wonder material&amp;rdquo; due to its exceptional properties such as superior electrical conductivity compared to copper and strength 200 times that of steel, had yet to exhibit the quantum phenomenon of superconductivity. However, in 2018, a remarkable discovery revealed that superconductivity could be achieved in Twisted Bilayer Graphene, a structure consisting of two layers of graphene placed on top of each other with a rotation angle near the &amp;ldquo;Magic Angle&amp;rdquo; of 1.1 degrees. These findings and many others have spurred a surge of research in the field of twistronics in experimental condensed matter physics, leading to the need for optimization and standardization of fabrication procedures for reproducibility and improve the quality of stacks. In this thesis, we aim to standardize the method of fabricating twisted Bilayer Graphene using the modified Dry Stacking Method and the recent technique of tear and stack procedure. We conclude with the successful implementation of a standardized step-by-step procedure for a typical TBLG stack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I. Plasma Instability in Hall Thrusters - An Analytical Study</title><link>https://example.com/project/plasma_i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/plasma_i/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hall Thrusters now plays a prominent role in space propulsion systems owing to its high thrust-to-power ratio, high specific impulse, high efficiency, and simple structure. Partial plasma confinement is fundamental to Hall Thrusters Physics, but that also leads to a variety of instabilities like Modified Two Stream Instability and Electron Cyclotron Drift Instability which takes a toll on efficiency and overall performance of the Thrusters. Although Numerical stimulations have replicated many of these, the cause of these instabilities are still in dark and it is of importance that we have a very solid theoretical understanding of Working Principles. Here, we derive a generic linear dispersion relation for Hall thrusters and attempt to analytically explain these observed instabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Symplectic Geometry</title><link>https://example.com/project/sympl_geo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/sympl_geo/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this report we study Symplectic Geometry, an outgrowth of classical mechanics. We give a comprehensible introduction and further provide an elementary introduction to its celebrated results in mathematical physics known as geometric quantization, a way of passing from a classical mechanical system to a quantum mechanical system by methods from symplectic geometry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Database GUI design.</title><link>https://example.com/project/gui_python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/gui_python/</guid><description>&lt;p>College Database&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unconventional Superconductivity</title><link>https://example.com/project/nius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/nius/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unconventional Superconductivity&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>