<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>math | Jovi K</title><link>https://example.com/tag/math/</link><atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>math</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu2110016f7bd3295c7cefa875f5c42664_171153_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>math</title><link>https://example.com/tag/math/</link></image><item><title>I. Plasma Instability in Hall Thrusters - An Analytical Study</title><link>https://example.com/project/plasma_i/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/plasma_i/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hall Thrusters now plays a prominent role in space propulsion systems owing to its high thrust-to-power ratio, high specific impulse, high efficiency, and simple structure. Partial plasma confinement is fundamental to Hall Thrusters Physics, but that also leads to a variety of instabilities like Modified Two Stream Instability and Electron Cyclotron Drift Instability which takes a toll on efficiency and overall performance of the Thrusters. Although Numerical stimulations have replicated many of these, the cause of these instabilities are still in dark and it is of importance that we have a very solid theoretical understanding of Working Principles. Here, we derive a generic linear dispersion relation for Hall thrusters and attempt to analytically explain these observed instabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Symplectic Geometry</title><link>https://example.com/project/sympl_geo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/sympl_geo/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this report we study Symplectic Geometry, an outgrowth of classical mechanics. We give a comprehensible introduction and further provide an elementary introduction to its celebrated results in mathematical physics known as geometric quantization, a way of passing from a classical mechanical system to a quantum mechanical system by methods from symplectic geometry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unconventional Superconductivity</title><link>https://example.com/project/nius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/nius/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unconventional Superconductivity&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>